A Guide to the Rockefeller Family Associates records, Elizabeth J. McCormack papers FA1228
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Family Associates records, Elizabeth J. McCormack papers
1975-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison) (1906-1978)
McCormack, Elizabeth
Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
FA1228
3 Cubic Feet 2 standard record storage boxes, 1 letter-sized document box.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted.
Scope and Contents
Elizabeth J. McCormack served as an associate for John D. Rockefeller 3rd and Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, and she later served as an associate for Laurance S. Rockefeller. The philanthropic interests of all three Rockefeller family members are represented in this small collection, including documentation of activities related to the Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, the Population Council, the Whitney Museum of American Art, the Commission on Private Philanthropy and Public Needs (The Filer Commission), the Synergos Institute, and Spelman College. Files often include Board and Committee records, correspondence, and reports.
Arrangement
Original order. Maintained as received.
- The Agricultural Development Council, Inc., 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- American Academy-Dramatic Arts, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Chamber Music Society, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Filer Commission Follow Up, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Japan Trip with Blanchette Rockefeller, 1979 May (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Museum of American Folk Art, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Rice High School - Harlem, NY, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Population Council, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Blanchette Rockefeller - Fieldwood Farm, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted material - Personnel
- American Ditchley Foundation, 1975-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Atlanta, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Corporate Angel Network, 1987-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Mailman Foundation (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Union Theological Seminary - Evaluation, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Esalen Institute (Revisioning Philosophy Program), 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Spelman College, 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 18-28)
  Scope and Contents
  Primarily contains meeting records including Board Meetings as well as records of the Executive Committee, Nominating Committee, and Policy Committee.
- Whitney Museum of American Art - Board, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, 1979-1996 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- The Synergos Institute, 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 32-34)
- Yale University - Program on Non-Profit Organizations, 1991-2000 (Box 3, Folder 35)